（C.卡伯波特）
片名:蝙蝠侠重现江湖
圣诞快乐 圣诞快乐
-Merry Christmas. -Merry Christmas.
（高谭市-33年后）
见到企鹅了，先睹为快
Penguin sighting! Man or myth?
是人还是谜，他是 今天专题，又见到企鹅了
What is he? Today's edition. Another penguin sighting.Another penguin sighting!
见到企鹅了，先睹为快
Check it out!
怪异企鹅人
Penguin man living in Gotham sewers!
住在高谭下水道中
Read all about the latest sighting!
快来看最新目击报导
请注意，高谭市
May l have your attention, Gotham City?
今晚点燃圣诞树的时刻 已经到了
lt is time for tonight's lighting of the tree.
好看吧？
How about that?
半人半企鹅，十分恐怖
Part man, part penguin! All horrifying!
只要五十分便能得知真相
Find out for only 50 cents! Come on!
快看看存在于我们脚下的 可能危险，快来看，各位
Read about the possible terror beneath our feet! Check it out!
快来看今天的报导
Read about it!
看看最新的企鹅怪物 目击报导
Missing link between man and bird.
是人与鸟间的缺失环节
My dear boy...
孩子，有时看那种垃圾 是种消遣
...sometimes it's a diversion to read such rubbish.
但多数时候是浪费时间
Usually, it's a waste of time.
随你说 今日专题，企鹅 快来看，人或谜？
Whatever. Today's issue! The Penguin! Man or myth?
“环球报”在此，25分
''The Globe''! Right here! 25 cents!
祝希望，也许加上些幸运
Well, here's hoping.
高谭可在漫长时期后 过第一个快乐圣诞节
With luck, Gotham will have its first merry Christmas in years.
我觉得很下流 在圣诞季节提起新发电厂
l feel almost vulgar at yuletide...
但我们若要动工兴建 就需要许可
...mentioning the new power plant. But if we're to break ground when we must, l'll need permits...
法规变通，减税鼓励 那类讨厌的微末小节
...variances, tax incentives. That sort of pesky nonsense.
发电厂？
Power plant?
麦斯，所有研究均显示
Studies show we've enough power to get
我们的电力 足以应付到下世纪中期
us into the middle of the next century.
你的分析家指的是 每年百分之一的人口成长
Your analysts foresee growth at 1% per annum.
那不是成长，是温和膨胀
That's a mild swelling.
试想像
lmagine...
一个高谭市
...a Gotham City...
在未来
...of the future,
灯光燃起如一片繁星 但却闪灭不定
lit up like a blanket of stars...but blinking on and off...
电力低得令人难堪
...embarrassingly low on juice.
老实说
Frankly...
我因而畏缩，市长先生
...l cringe, Mr. Mayor.
抱歉，你的任何计划
Sorry, any plans must go
都得循正常管道 向负责委员会申请
to the usual committees...through the usual channels.
我有个建议
l have a suggestion.
好的...
Well...
事实上更算是个问题
...actually, really, just more like a question.
恐怕我们未适当训练 凯尔小姐
l'm afraid we haven't properly housebroken Ms. Kyle.
但她有个优点 她泡的咖啡非常香
ln the plus column, though...she makes great coffee.
爸
Dad?
市长先生 该下去为大众带来喜悦了
Mr. Mayor? Time to go down and bring joy to the masses.
天！ “事实上更算是个问题”
''Actually, more of a question.''
你这个笨蛋
You stupid corn dog.
天！笨蛋，笨蛋
Corn dog, corn dog.
我光靠许瑞克员工 便可取得足以重选的签名
l have enough signatures from Shreck employees to warrant a recall.
那不是威胁 只是单纯数据
That's not a threat, just simple numbers.
也许
Maybe.
但你没有立场 而且也没有候选人
But you sure as hell don't have an issue or a candidate.
哈，许瑞克先生 非常感谢各位女士先生
Thank you, Ladies and Gentlemen.
祝我们市政府的人 和你们所有人-假期快乐
From those of us at City Hall to each and every one of you......Happy Holidays.
今晚有位不需介绍的人 与我们同在
We have with us a man who needs no introduction,
他对本市贡献良多
he's given us so much.
请欢迎高谭市的圣诞老人 麦斯许瑞克
Please welcome Gotham's own Santa Claus, Max Shreck.
到人事处拿那些合约
Pick up those contracts from Personnel and...
再去拿干洗衣物和纸巾
...pick up the dry cleaning and paper towels.
糟糕
Darn!
忘了我的讲稿
Forgot my speech.
提醒我教训那个叫什么的
Remind me to take it out on what's-her-name.
圣诞老人？恐怕不是
Santa Claus?Afraid not.
我只是个低贱的走运笨蛋
l'm just a poor schmo. Got lucky.
我要回馈你们若不满意 就告我吧
Sue me...if l want to give some back.
但愿我能送出的 不只是昂贵的玩具
l only wish l could hand out more than just...expensive baubles.
但愿我能送出世界和平
l wish l could hand out world peace...
和无条件的爱
...and unconditional love...
包在大蝴蝶结中
...wrapped in a big bow.
但是你可以 你会的！
Oh, but you can.Oh, but you will.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
好主意
Great idea.
不是我的主意
Not mine.
你在等什么？发出讯号
Give the signal!
我们要大角色 主导一切的那个家伙
We want the big guy! The guy who runs the show!
你要什么？ 不是你
What do you want?Not you!
许瑞克 你得先过我这一关
Shreck!You'll have to go through me.
奇普！
Chip
爸，走，救你自已
Dad! Go! Save yourself!
爸，走！
Dad, go!
不！ 闭嘴！
Shut up!
再上前一步，蝙蝠侠先生 我就...
Take one step closer, Mr. Manbat, and l'll--
没打中
Missed.
是那位蝙蝠侠
The Batman.
或只是蝙蝠侠
Or is it just ''Batman''?
当然，任你选择
Your choice, of course.
真是短暂
Well, that was... ...very brief.
就和我生命中的 所有男人一样
Just like all the men in my life.
什么男人？
What men?
但是...
Well...
但话说回来，还有你 不过你需要治疗
...then again, there's you. But you need therapy.
谢谢你拯救我们，蝙蝠侠 恐怕马戏团帮又回来了
Thanks for saving the day, Batman. The Circus Gang is back.
静观后效吧
We'll see.
他们差点捉走麦斯许瑞克
They almost made off with our mover and shaker, Max Shreck.
那令人难以忍受的混蛋呢
Where is that insufferable bastard?
（动物园）
（极地世界）
嗨
Hi
相信你搜寻的字眼是...
l believe the word you're looking for is...
事实上 这一切只是个恶梦
Actually, this is all just a bad dream.
你在家中床上 无比宁静，安适的憩息着
You're at home in bed... ...heavily sedated, resting comfortably...
因你毕生牟取暴利 而吐出的致癌物而垂死
...dying from the carcinogens you've personally spewed... ...in a lifetime of profiteering.
是悲剧性的讽刺 或诗般的正义？你告诉我
Tragic irony... ...or poetic justice? You tell me.
我的天，是真的 下水道的企鹅人
My God, it's true. Penguin Man of the sewer.
奇异的是，麦斯 你和我有些共通之处
Odd as it may seem, Max... ...you and l have something in common.
我们受孕时都如怪物
We're both perceived as monsters.
然而...
But somehow...
你是个倍受敬重的怪物 而我则不然
...you're a well-respected monster... ...and l am, to date... ...not!
老实说，我不以为然 我是个生意人
Frankly, l feel that's a bum rap. l'm a businessman.
强硬，对，刻薄，也行 但还不足使我成为怪物
Tough, yes. Shrewd, okay. But that does not make me a monster.
别糗自己了，麦斯 我对你一清二楚
Don't embarrass yourself, Max! l know all about you.
你隐藏，我发掘
What you hide, l discover.
你弃于马桶中的 我将它保存起来，明白吗
What you put in your toilet... ...l place on my mantle. Get the picture?
那是什么？ 打算对我催眠吗？
ls that supposed to hypnotize me?
不，只是要让你头痛欲裂
Just give you a splitting headache.
没有效
lt's not working.
真没有，只是空包弹
Oh, you big baby! Just blanks.
今晚我大费周章 只为杀你吗？
Would l go through all this trouble just to kill you?
不，麦斯 我有个全然不同的目的
No, Max. l have an entirely other purpose.
我准备好了，麦斯
l'm ready, Max.
我已在下面太久
l've been down here too long.
我该上升了
lt's time for me to ascend...
重新出现
...to re-emerge...
藉着你的帮助
...with your help...
你的深谙其道，你的机伶
...your know-how... ...your savvy.
我并非生于下水道
l wasn't born in the sewer, you know.
我来自...和你一样
l come from... ...like you.
而和你一样，我要尊重
And, like you, l want some respect!
得到我的基本人权
A recognition of my basic humanity.
但最重要的...
But most of all...
我要藉找到我父母 来查出我是谁
...l want to find out who l am... ...by finding my parents...
得知我的姓名
...learning my human name.
高谭人视为当然的 简单事物
Simple stuff that the good people of Gotham take for granted!
我到底为何得帮你？
And... ...exactly why am l going to help you? Well....
我们开始吧
Let's start.
这是什么？
Let's see what we have in here.
一些你那干净纺织厂的 有毒废水
A batch of toxic waste... ...from your clean textile plant!
这种废物后面有一大池
There's a whole lagoon of this crud in the back!
那可能来自任何地方
lt could be from anywhere.
证明你拥有高谭市 半数易燃建筑的文件呢？
What about the documents that prove you own half of the firetraps in Gotham City?
若有那种文件...
lf there were such documents...
而且我不承认有... 我也早已将它们切碎了
...that's not an admission... ...they would've been shredded.
好主意
Good idea.
许多胶带和一点耐心 情况便截然不同
A lot of tape and a little patience make all the difference.
对了
By the way...
你的老合伙人 佛列德亚特金好吗？
...how's Fred Atkins, your old partner?
佛列德？
Fred?
我相信他正在度延长假期 他...很好
Fred's actually... ...l believe he's on an extended vacation. He's good.
他很好
Good.
你好，麦斯，记得我吗？ 我是佛列德的手
Hiya, Max. Remember me? l'm Fred's hand!
要向其他部份肢体致意吗
Want to greet any other body parts?
记住 你摒弃的，我珍惜
Remember, Max... ...you flush it, l flaunt it.
你知道吗，企鹅先生
You know what, Mr. Penguin, sir?
我想或许...我能协助你 筹划一个欢迎返乡的策略
l think, perhaps... ...l could help orchestrate a ''Welcome Home'' scenario for you.
等我们俩都回到家 或许我们能互相帮助
Once back home, perhaps we could help each other.
你不会后悔的 许瑞克先生
You won't regret this, Mr. Shreck.
亲爱的，我回来了
Honey, l'm home!
我忘了，我未婚
Oh, l forgot. l'm not married.
猫咪小姐
Miss Kitty.
从你拒绝分享的 性胡闹活动归来了吗
Back from more sexual escapades you refuse to share?
不是我爱刺探
Not that l'd ever pry.
喝你的晚餐吧
Drink your dinner.
什么？
What?
怎么会有人如此可悲？
How can anyone be so pathetic?
对，对你而言我是可悲
Yes, to you l seem pathetic. But l'm a working girl.
但我是个上班女郎 得付房租
你若能贡献点生活费 而不要开溜就好了
Must pay the rent. Maybe if you chipped in instead of stepping out.
瑟琳娜亲爱的，是妈
Selina, dear, it's your mother.
只是打电话问候你一下 对，但是...
Just calling to say hello. Yeah, but...
但是我很失望 你不回家过圣诞节
But l'm disappointed you're not coming home for Christmas.
我要和你讨论
l want to discuss why you insist on languishing in Gotham City...
你为何要像低级秘书般 坚持要在高谭市受折磨
...as some lowly secretary.
是低级助理
Lowly assistant.
瑟琳娜，记得我们的 圣诞出游计划吗？
Selina, about that Christmas getaway we planned...
我将要独自去
l'm going alone.
萧博士说我需要独处 而非附属品
Dr. Shaw says l need to be my own person, not an appendage.
真是个附属品
Some appendage!
瑟琳娜凯尔的答录机盛宴 永不停息
The party never stops on Selina Kyle's answering machine.
看来上次打板球时 我该让他赢的
l should've let him win that last racquetball game.
哈，瑟琳娜凯尔
Hello... ...Selina Kyle.
我们要告诉你有种新的 高谭女士香水
We're calling to tell you about exciting new Gotham Lady perfume.
它会使女人感觉像女人 而且男人不会有抱怨
lt makes women feel like women... and the men have no complaints either.
嗨，瑟琳娜，这是你自己 真蠢
Hi Selina
提醒你，你得回办公室去
This is yourself reminding you to come all the way back to the office...
除非你记得带 布鲁斯韦恩的档案回家
-...if you forgot the Bruce Wayne file--
因为会议在周三 你这个笨蛋
-You stupid corn dog!
（许瑞克百货公司）
加班吗？
Working late?
我只是在帮你预备明早 和布鲁斯韦恩开会的资料
l'm just boning up for your Bruce Wayne meeting in the morning.
我调出发电厂企划案的 所有档案和...
l pulled all of the files on the proposed power plant...
预备请韦恩先生 投资的文件
...and Mr. Wayne's investment.
我甚至打开了保护档 多勤奋啊
l even opened the protected files--How industrious!
你是如何打开保护档的
How did you open the protected files?
我能问吗？
May l ask?
我想你的密码是吉拉多 你的吉娃娃的名字
l figured your password was ''Geraldo,'' your chihuahua, and it was.
这实在非常有趣
This is all very interesting,
虽然在技术上有一点难懂
though a bit on the technical side...
我是指发电厂 如何只在名义上是发电厂
...about how the power plant is a power plant in name only...
而事实上，它将是个 巨大的容电器？
...since, in fact, it's going to be a big, giant... ...big, giant...capacitor.
它不会产电力 反而会吸收高谭市的...
And, instead of generating power, it'll be sucking power from...
电力，并贮存起来
...Gotham City... ...and storing it...
囤积它
...stockpiling it...
我得说那是个 非常新奇的方式
...which is a very novel approach, l'd say.
那你会将此事告诉谁？
Who'd you say this to?
没有人
Nobody.
好奇会使猫如何呢？
What did curiosity do to the cat?
我不是猫 我只是个助理，一个秘书
l'm no cat. l'm just an assistant. A secretary.
而且是非常好的一个
And a very good one.
太好了
Too good?
听着，那是我们的秘密 真的
Listen... ...it's our secret. Honest.
你怎能对一个无意义的人 如此残忍？
How can you be so mean to someone so meaningless? This power plant...
这发电厂将是我的传家宝 是我遗留下来的
...is my legacy. lt's what l leave behind. For Chip.
留给奇普 任何事都无法阻止
Nothing must prevent that.
好，动手吧
OK,Go ahead.
恐吓我，欺压我 若能使你觉得强大
lntimidate me. Bully me, if it makes you feel big.
反正你又不可能杀了我
lt's not like you can kill me!
事实上就有可能
Actually, it's a lot like that.
什么？
What?
你知道，有那么一秒 你真的吓到我了
For a second, you really frightened me.
真的吗？
Really?!
亲爱的，我回来了
Honey, l'm home!
我忘了，我未婚
Oh, l forgot. l'm not married.
瑟琳娜，我是妈 打电话给我
Selina, this is your mother. Call me.
瑟琳娜，我是妈 你为何没回我电话
Selina, this is your mother. Why haven't you called me back?
哈，瑟琳娜凯尔
Hello, Selina Kyle.
我们打电话，是想确定 你已试用过高谭女士香水
We're just calling to make sure you've tried Gotham Lady perfume.
在办公室只要喷一下 你老板会要你下班留下
One whiff of this and your boss will ask you to stay after work...
开二人烛光员工会议
...for a candlelight staff meeting for two.
高谭女士香水 许瑞克百货公司仅售
Gotham Lady perfume. Exclusively at Shreck's department store.
不！
No
我不知道你觉得如何 猫咪小姐
l don't know about you, Miss Kitty, but l feel...
但我觉得...可口多了
...so much yummier.
女士先生们
Ladies and gentlemen;
我再度在你们面前
l stand before you again to denounce the urban chaos
遣责似乎与我们共存于 这伟大城市的都市紊乱
we live with in our city.
它得停止 也定能得阻止
lt's got to stop.lt's going to stop!
在这应该聚合的时节
Our community is coming apart... ...in a season when it should be coming together.
我们的社区正在崩离 我不在乎批评者会怎么说
l don't care what the cynics may say. This is the Christmas season...
现在是圣诞时节 应该是愈合的时候
...and should be a healing time.
我不只以官员的身份声明 更以丈夫与父亲的立场说
l say that not only as an official... ...but as a husband and a father.
昨晚的暴行不会再发生
Last night's violence won't happen again.
我不太善于言词 因此我只能说，谢了
l'm not good at speeches, so l'll just say, ''Thanks.''
天，是可怕的企鹅人
lt's the hideous Penguin Man.
来，孩子带走 但请别伤害我的孩子
Just don't hurt my baby, please.
这是数分钟前在高谭广场 发生的非凡情况
This was the remarkable scene only minutes ago in Gotham Plaza.
神秘的企鹅解救市长之子 并宣布他的存在
The mysterious Penguin saving the life of the Mayor's baby -then announcing his presence.
我要的回报 是找到我父母的机会
-All l want in return...is a chance...to find my Mom and Dad.
一个查出他们是谁...
A chance to find out who they are...
及我是谁的机会
...and thusly... ...who l am.
然后，由我父母处
And then... ...with my parents...
设法了解为什么...
...try to understand...why.
为何他们做出 他们觉得非做不可的事
Why they did what l guess they felt they had to do...
对一个孩子...
...to a child...
一个生来有点不同的孩子
...who was born... ...a little different.
一个在下水道渡过 第一个圣诞节...
A child... ...who spent his first Christmas...
及其后许多个...的孩子
...and many since... ...in a sewer.
韦恩先生？有何不对吗？ 没有
Mr. Wayne? Something wrong?
他的父母
His parents.
再度说明 本画面直接拍自高谭广场
This scene, direct from Gotham Plaza.
但愿他找到他们
l hope he finds them.
他在那里，站在高谭市 领导人物麦斯许瑞克旁边
There he is, standing alongside Gotham's leading citizen,
Max Shreck. How about a statement? People want to know.
（档案室）
企鹅不能受打扰 档案室是公共场所
-Penguin's not to be disturbed! -lt's a public place!
你违反宪法第一修正案 妨碍新闻自由    走开
-Walk. Now. Move. -Freedom of the press!
等一下
Wait a minute.
那尊严隐密的 重新发掘你的根的自由呢
What about the freedom to rediscover your roots... ...with dignity in privacy?
怎么，许瑞克先生 企鹅是你的私人好友吗？
ls the Penguin a personal friend?
是，他是全市的私人好友 因此，发发慈悲吧
He's a personal friend of the whole city, so have a heart.
让宪法休息一下，好吗 现在是圣诞时期
Give the Constitution a rest. lt's Christmas.
“红三角马戏团 推出猛狮精彩表演”
''Red Triangle Circus put on a swell show with fierce lions.
“马戏团回来表演两周 孩子们会爱...”谢谢
''Circus returns for two weeks-- ''Kids will love--'' Thanks.
是冷的 是马铃薯奶油浓汤，先生
Cold! lt's vichyssoise.
本来就该是冷的
lt's supposed to be cold.
“马戏团带着畸型人回来 可能不适小孩观看”
''Circus is back with a freak show. May not be suitable for kids.
“有狮子狗女士...”
''Featuring a poodle lady...
“世上最快的人 和极地鸟男孩”
''...the world's fattest man... ''...and Aquatic Bird Boy.''
你为何决心证明 这个企鹅所言不实
Why are you determined to prove... ...that this Penguin is not what he seems?
你一定得当全城 唯一的“人兽”吗？
Must you be the only lonely ''man-beast'' in town?
“在数个城镇发生无数 儿童失踪案件后”
''Circus folded its tents yesterday... ''
“马戏团昨天收起帐篷 也许永远不能再演出”
...after reports of missing children in several towns.
警方已关闭红三角表演场
''Police have closed down the Red Triangle's fairgrounds.
然而至少一名畸型表演者 在接受侦讯前失踪了
''However, at least one freak show performer vanished before... ''...he could be questioned.''
我想你觉得好多了，先生
l suppose you feel better now.
没有
No.
事实上，我觉得更糟
Actually, l feel worse.
你为何还在外面
Why're you still out?
你是在关心那个奇怪 英雄般的企鹅人物吗
Are you concerned about that strange, heroic Penguin person?
我想他知道他父母是谁
l think he knows who his parents are.
他另有所图
There's something else.
企鹅先生... 企鹅是不会飞的鸟
Mr. Penguin... A penguin is a bird that cannot fly!
我是个人
l am a man!
我有名字
l have a name!
奥兹瓦卡伯波特
Oswald Cobblepot!
卡伯波特先生 你永无机会与父母和解了
You'll never be able to settle with them?
没错
True.
我是他们的长子
l was their ''Number One'' son...
他们却视我如粪土
...and they treated me like number two.
但害怕非自然之物是人性
But it's human nature to fear... ...the unusual.
也许当我用晶亮的鳍 拿着我的宝贵婴儿玩具
Perhaps... ...when l held my... ...Tiffany baby rattle... ...with a shiny flipper...
而非五根胖手指时
...instead of five chubby digits...
他们惊怕了
...they freaked.
但我原谅他们
But l forgive them.
企鹅原谅父母 “我对自己与世界 都感到平和”
Penguin forgives parents! ''l'm at peace with myself and the world! ''
“只要有心 便不需要手”
''Don't need hands as long as you got heart.''
“我的心充满爱 我觉得有五尺高”
''My heart is filled with love. l feel five feet tall.''
他像只变成王子的青蛙 不，他更像只企鹅
-He's like a frog that became a prince. -No, he's more like a penguin.
好了，漂亮的小东西 乖乖听话
Now, now, pretty little thing.
我最喜欢高大强壮
Nice and easy.
又不怕对体型小一半的人 展现力量的人
l just love a big man who's not afraid to show it with someone half his size.
温柔待我 这是我的第一次
Be gentle, it's my first time.
井字游戏
Tic, tac, toe.
对了，我... 你使自己容易受害
You make it easy, don't you?
总是等着蝙蝠侠来救你
Always waiting for some Batman to save you.
我是猫女
l am Catwoman...
听我怒吼
...hear me roar.
我想请你喝咖啡 但我的助理正在休假
l'd offer you coffee, but my assistant is using her vacation time.
好时机，反正过年之前
Good time. Everyone but
除了拦路大盗 大家都会减少活动
the bandits'll be slacking off till after New Year.
我不确定是否喜欢 你的推论，布鲁斯
Not sure l like the inference.
抱歉，麦斯 未发觉我有做推论
Didn't realize l made one.
我现在促销发电厂计划 因为将来花费将更高
l'm pushing this power plant now because it'll cost more later.
省一百万等于赚一百万
A million saved is a million earned.
我做了这份报告 也许你想看看
l commissioned this report. Take a look at it.
麦斯，重点是 高谭市已供电过量
Gotham City has a power surplus.
我确信你知道
l'm sure you know that.
我的问题是... 你的目的为何？
My question is... ...what's your angle?
供电过量？布鲁斯 你该惭愧，没那回事
Power surplus? Bruce, shame on you!
电力再多都不为过
No such thing. One can never have too much power.
我的生命若有何意义 那就是意义
lf my life has a meaning, that's the meaning.
我将与你唱反调
l'll fight you.
我已和市长谈过 我们看法一致，因此...
l've already spoken to the Mayor and we agree.
市长多如过江之鲫 贵族容易没落
Mayors come and go. Blue bloods tire easily.
你以为能和拳王许瑞克 打上十五回合吗？
Can you go 15 rounds with Muhammad Shreck?
看来得拭目以待
l guess we'll find out.
当然，我没有卡伯波特 那种犯罪集团首领支持
Of course, l don't have a crime boss like Cobblepot in my corner.
因此，也许... 犯罪集团首领？
Crime boss?!
证明你知道什么？ 天之骄子先生
Shows what you know...
奥兹瓦是高谭的新英雄
...Mr. To-the-manor-born- with-a-silver-spoon. Oswald is Gotham's new golden boy.
他父母若未嫌弃他 你们俩或许会是校舍室友
lf his parents hadn't 86'ed him, you'd have been bunkies at prep school.
奥兹瓦控制红三角帮
He controls the Red Triangle Gang.
我还无法证明 但我们都知道...
l can't prove it yet, but we both--
韦恩，我不允许办公室内 有揭人隐私之举
l'll not stand for mud-slinging here.
我助理若在此
lf my assistant was here, she'd have already escorted you out.
早已护送你出去... 到任何他要去之处
Anywhere he wants.
可能是夜总会、岩穴 或隐密的藏身处
Preferably some nightspot grotto... ...or... ...secluded hideaway.
好西装 谢谢
Nice suit.
瑟琳娜
Selina
瑟琳娜，瑟琳娜 那是我的名字，百万麦斯
Selina Selina
别念太多磨坏 否则我要你买个新的赔我
That's my name, don't wear it out or l'll make you buy me a new one.
瑟琳娜
Selina
这是布鲁斯...韦恩
This is Bruce... ...Wayne.
是，我们见过
We've met.
有吗？  抱歉 我误以为自己是别人
Have we? No, l'm sorry. l mistook me for somebody else.
你是指我吧？
You mean, ''mistook me.''
我误以为我...对 我是那么说的吗？
lsn't that what l said?
不，我想不是
l don't think so.
怎么回事？
What happened?
你在滑雪坡上受伤了吗？
Did you hurt yourself... on that ski slope?
因此你才缩短假期回来？
ls that why you cut short your vacation? Came back?
很模糊
lt's a blur.
我是说，未完全失去记忆
Not complete amnesia.
我记得玛丽玛格丽特修女 在教堂呕吐
l remember Sister Mary Margaret puking in church.
贝西莱利说那是害喜
And Betsy saying it was morning sickness.
我也记得有次上学 忘了穿内裤
And the time l forgot to wear my underpants to school...
而注意到的男孩 名叫瑞奇佛莱伯格
...and the name of the boy who noticed was Ricky Friedburg.
他已经死了
He's dead now.
但昨晚却完全模糊
But last night... ...complete blur.
很不可思议吧？
Couldn't you just die?
瑟琳娜
Selina
拜托
Please...
送韦恩先生出去
...show out Mr. Wayne.
乐意之至
With pleasure.
你的外套，韦恩先生
Your coat, Mr. Wayne.
你不像是会和 许瑞克先生做生意的人
You don't seem like the type who does business with Shreck.
你也不像是 会服从他的命令的人
Nor you, the type to take orders from him. Well, that's a...
说来话长 我可以腾出一些时间
...long story. l could free up some time.
我的电话有登记 我受诱惑  我得工作
-l'm listed. -l'm tempted. l'm working.
我要走了
l'm leaving.
爸，你相信她说的吗？ 女人
You buy that blurry business? Women.
除了你已逝的母亲 任何事我都不讶异，奇普
Nothing surprises me. Except your late mother.
谁会想到瑟琳娜 竟有能毁坏的脑袋
Who'd have thought Selina had a brain to damage?
最坏结果吗？ 她企图勒索我
Bottom line? She tries to blackmail me,
我将她推出更高的窗 此时，我有更重要的事
l'll drop her out of a higher window.Meantime l've got badder fish to fry.
奥兹瓦，我是麦斯
Oswald... ...it's Max.
你在家吗？
You're home?
你好吗？
How you been?
你的家人，有家庭真好
Your extended family. Good to have a family.
我现在宁可不受打扰
l'd rather not be disturbed now.
下楼，奥兹瓦 我要给你一个惊喜
Come on downstairs, Oswald. l have a surprise.
我不喜欢惊喜
l don't like surprises.
下来吧
Come on.
别偷看
Don't peek.
你会破坏惊喜的
You'll spoil it.
对，奉承是个重担 我很清楚
Adulation is a cross to bear. God knows l know.
但在进步的道路上 有人得代替我们的名气
But someone's got to supplant our standing in the way of progress.
别否认，卡伯波特先生 你有那种魔力
And don't deny it, Mr. Cobblepot, you've got the magic.
你的非凡魅力远胜我们 下来吧
Your charisma's bigger than both of us. Come on down.
市长
Mayor.
市长，麦斯
十一月选举 现在不是才十二月末吗
Elections happen in November. lt's late December.
不用担心
Don't worry.
我要你见珍和乔希 我的形象顾问
l want you to meet Jen and Josh, my image consultants.
来，拾回你天生的权利
Here. Reclaim your birthright.
我是珍，嗨
l'm Jen.
好，我看看
Okay, let's see.
首先我要做的是 将这些小手套戴在你手上
What l'd like to do first is put these gloves on you.
我们的研究显示 我们的选民喜欢手指
Our research tells us that voters like fingers.
因此，若将它藏起来 我们...
So if we were to just lose this....
我们改天再戴，好吗？
We'll do it another time.
下水道没多少 能反光的平面，对吧？
Not a lot of reflective surfaces in the sewer, huh?
不过，原可能更糟 我的鼻子可能血流不止
Still, could be worse. My nose could be gushing blood.
你的鼻子可能...
What do you mean by that?
所有人回去工作
Everybody, back to work!
我们来创造一个市长
Let's make... ...a mayor!
说得对，我们错过 正常排定的选举
You're right, we missed the regular election...
但当选官员可以改选 弹劾
...but elected officials can be recalled.
罢黜，像尼克森
Given the boot. Look at Nixon, Agnew.
艾格纽，再想想你 奥兹瓦卡伯波特填补其位
Then think of you... ...Oswald Cobblepot, filling the void.
我倒想填补她
l'd like to fill her void.
我们需要签名以促成改选 那些我能供应，奥兹瓦
We'll need signatures to overturn the ballot. l can supply those.
教她我的法国鳍把戏
-Teach her my French flipper trick.
奥兹瓦 我们还需要一样东西
-We need one more thing.
一块踏板吗？
A platform?
停止环球温室效应 开始环球冷却效应
Stop global warming. Start global cooling.
使世界成为巨大冰箱
Make the world an icebox.
我喜欢，但要改选市长 需要一个触媒，导火线
l like it. But to get the Mayor recalled, we must have a catalyst.
“你做得很好 卡伯波特市长”
''You're doing great, Mayor Cobblepot.''
“你的餐桌准备好了 卡伯波特市长”
''Your table is ready, Mayor Cobblepot.''
“我需要你，奥兹瓦 我现在就需要你”
''l need you, Oswald. l need you now.''
“那是我见过最大的伞”
''That's the biggest parasol l've ever seen.''
很快就会发生东京湾意外 及雷斯塔格大火之类事件
Soon an incident like the Gulf of Tonkin, or the Reichstag fire...
你要我上面的老朋友 使市长发狂吗？  正是
You want my old friends up there... ...to drive the Mayor into a foaming frenzy?
听来很好玩
-Exactly. -Sounds fun. But...
但我不能分神，麦斯 我有我的正事要办
...l mustn't get sidetracked, Maxie.
分神，奥兹瓦？
l have my own things to tend to.
现在你有机会实现
Sidetracked? This is your chance to fulfill a destiny...
这是被你父母 草率抛弃的天命
...your parents carelessly discarded.
你是指重拾我天生权利
Reclaim my birthright, you mean?
试想身为市长后 你将得到媒体的注意
lmagine, as Mayor, you have the ear of the media...
企业大亨将尊重你的意见 无限嬉闹
...access to the captains of industry... ...unlimited poontang.
你的条件很诱人，麦斯
You drive a hard bargain, Maxie.
好吧，我就当市长
All right, l'll be Mayor.
烧吧，宝贝，烧吧！
Burn, baby, burn! !
她是谁？ 她是什么？
-Who is she? -What is she?
我不知道是要开火 或坠入爱河
l don't know whether to open fire or fall in love.
可怜虫 手枪和私处老是搞不清楚
You poor guys. Always confusing your pistols with your privates.
别伤害我们，小姐 我们的薪水不到三百块
Don't hurt us. Our take-home's under 300.
薪水太高了，滚吧
You're overpaid. Hit the road.
尽管打我吧
Go ahead and hit me.
欣赏你的作品吗？
Admiring your handiwork?
参观暴乱场面
Touring the riot scene.
沉重的评估破坏情况
Gravely assessing the devastation.
尽荣耀的市长职责
Upstanding-Mayor stuff.
你不是市长
You're not Mayor.
世事多变
Things change.
你有何企图？
What do you want?
好直接
The direct approach.
我欣赏一个戴面具的人 能如此
l admire that in a man with a mask.
你不会真的以为你赢吧
You don't really think you'll win, do you?
世事多变
Things change.
我先看到她的，得走了
l saw her first. Got to fly.
你怎么如此？我是个女人
How could you? l'm a woman!
对不起，我...
l'm sorry.
如我所说，我是个女人 不能让人视为理所当然
As l was saying, l'm a woman and can't be taken for granted.
人生无常，我也是
Life's a bitch, now so am l.
你是谁？
Who are you?
蝙蝠背后是什么人？
Who's the man behind the bat?
也许你能帮我找出...
Maybe you can help me find...
在猫背后的女人
...the woman... ...behind the cat.
不，那不是你
No, that's not you.
这才是你
Here you are.
被猫便盒救了一条命
Saved by kitty litter.
混蛋！
Bastard!
阿福
Alfred...
帮我拿消毒软膏来，好吗
...bring me some antiseptic ointment.
来了，会痛吗？先生
Coming. Are you in pain, sir?
不太会
Not really.
谢谢... 我或许救了市长的宝贝
l may have saved the Mayor's baby...
但我拒绝救如婴儿般 束手无策的市长
...but l refuse to save a mayor... ...who stood by, helpless as a baby...
使高谭市遭到破坏
...while Gotham was ravaged by a disease...
使老鹰童子军 患病成为疯狂小丑
...that turned Eagle Scouts into crazed clowns...
快乐的主妇变成猫女 谢谢
...and happy homemakers into catwomen. Thank you.
奥兹瓦卡伯波特 吸引高谭市的神秘兽人
Oswald Cobblepot, the mystery man-beast, Thank you.
今天宣布要竞选高谭市长 谢谢
made his bid to run Gotham.
卡伯波特先生 你是年轻人的最佳模范
Mr. Cobblepot, you are the coolest role model a young person could have.
你是模范能得到的 最热情年轻人
And you're the hottest young person... ...a role model could have.
来
Here.
戴个徽章
Wear a button.
让我帮你戴在这里
Let me just get it on here.
谢谢你们...
Thank you.
我真的会喜欢上 候选市长这种事
This mayor stuff is not about power, it's about reaching out to people.
非关权力，而是接触人民 触摸人民，抚摸人民
Touching people. Groping people.
企鹅，有个... 我不叫企鹅！
-Penguin-- -My name is not Penguin!
我是奥兹瓦卡伯波特
lt's Oswald Cobblepot.
奥兹瓦，有人要见你
Oswald, there's somebody here to see you.
正是我在找的女人
Just the pussy l've been looking for.
这里真冷
lt's chilly in here.
我会使你温暖 冷静，奥兹瓦
l'll warm you. Down, Oswald.
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
你瞧 你和我有共通点
You see... ...you and l have something in common.
听来很熟悉
Sounds familiar.
毁灭的癖好？ 对流行大师的鄙视？
Appetite for destruction? Contempt for czars of fashion?
等等，别告诉我 赤裸裸的性魅力？
Wait, don't tell me. Naked sexual charisma?
蝙蝠侠
Batman.
我们的共同仇敌 药膏中的苍蝇
The thorn in both our sides. The fly in our ointment.
药膏？
Ointment?
我会有气味和无气味的 我会再回来
l've got scented and unscented. l'll come back later.
对了，你是登记投票人吗 我是市长候选人
Perchance, are you a registered voter? l'm a mayoral prospect.
我今天只有一个目的 打倒蝙蝠
l have but one pet cause today. Ban the Bat.
又是他，没问题 他已经完了，你看
Oh, him again. No bother. He's already history. Check it out.
我们要拆开他的蝙蝠车 将它变成活动氢弹
We'll disassemble his Batmobile and turn it into an H-bomb on wheels.
不，不
No,
他的力量比殉教者还大
He'd have even more power as a martyr.
要消灭蝙蝠侠
To destroy Batman, we must
首先得将他变成 他最痛恨的人
first turn him into what he hates the most.
意即，我们
Namely, us.
你是指陷害他？
Frame him?
还没上任就有黑名单了？
Not even in office yet and already an enemies list.
那些名字不能任人窥探
Those names are not for prying eyes.
我为何要信任一个猫女？
Why should l trust some catbroad anyway?
也许你只是个 心理不平衡的名媛
Maybe you're a screwed-up sorority chick getting back at daddy...
为父亲未在十六岁时 买那只小马而生报复之心
...for not buying her that pony when she turned 16.
好鸟，对
Nice birdie.
好猫...
Nice kitty. Nice kitty.
蝙蝠侠伤了我的手臂
Batman napalmed my arm.
在我才开始满意自己时 就害我跌落谷底
He knocked me off a building just when l started to feel good about myself.
我要在他坠落时 扮演重要角色
l want to play an integral part in his degradation.
计划正在形成
A plan is forming.
我要参加
l want in.
想到要害蝙蝠侠 就令我觉得...
The thought of busting Batman makes me feel all...
肮脏
...dirty.
或许我就在这儿 给自己洗个澡
Maybe l'll just give myself a bath right here.
我向市长挑战
l challenge the Mayor...
明晚在高谭广场 重点圣诞树
...to relight the Christmas tree in Gotham Plaza tomorrow night.
他得证明...
Sir, shall we change
先生，要换台 看有尊严品味的节目吗
the channel to a program with some dignity and class?
或许可看“爱的连线”
''The Love Connection'' perhaps?
并非我对市长有信心
l have no faith in the Mayor.
但我盼望祈祷 蝙蝠侠能出现，维护和平
But l hope and pray... ...that Batman... ...will be present to preserve the peace.
非常感谢你们，谢谢 狡猾
Subtle.
你为何如此做？
Why are you doing this?
瑟琳娜？
Selina?
抱歉，我无意吓你 吓我？不，是我在吓自己
Sorry, l didn't mean to scare you. Scare me? l was just scaring myself.
我不明白，但很高兴见你 离开许瑞克，置身俗世中 是
l don't see how, but.... lt's nice to see you in the real world, away from Shreck.
很高兴能在这里
lt's nice to be here.
你没事吧？
You okay?
你似乎得了假期忧郁症
You look like you have the holiday blues or something.
天，近来的事，真怪异
Boy, the news these days. Weird!
听电视说估计猫女 重140磅
l heard on TV that Catwoman weighs 140 pounds.
不知这些烂记者 晚上怎么睡得着
How do these hacks sleep at night?
甚至不精确 蝙蝠侠毁了它
lt's not even accurate. ''Batman blows it.''
光是财产损失方面 他可能就救了百万元
He probably saved millions in property damage.
你不会是要去看 重新点燃圣诞树吧
You're not going to the relighting of the tree, are you?
不是，我不想死在那里
l wouldn't be caught dead there.
今晚将是冷漠城市的 热情之夜
lt's going to be a hot time on a cold town tonight.
你有黑暗的一面，对吧？
You got kind of a dark side, don't you?
不比你黑暗，布鲁斯
No darker than yours.
你何不到我家去 我们可以一起看电视
Why don't you come over and we can watch it on TV?
什么？
The tree-lighting ceremony.
点树灯仪式 不行，我今晚得到别地
l can't. l have to be somewhere tonight.
来吃顿提早的晚餐如何 五点？六点？
How about coming for dinner at 5? Let's say 6?
好，五点 五点，你和我，好
Five. Five. You and me.
树灯熄灭，然后我按钮
The tree lights up and then l push the button.
不，慢着... 我按钮，然后树灯亮
Wait, wait. l push the button, then the tree lights up.
你是谁？ 星探
Who are you? Talent scout.
进来
Come in.
你知道，我不是只会点树灯 我还是个女演员
l don't just light trees. l'm an actress as well.
那是什么？相机吗？
What is that thing? A camera or something?
说“起士”
Say ''Cheese!''
起士
Cheese.
谢谢阿福
Thanks, Alfred.
我确信他是个好...同伴
l'm sure he's wonderful company...
但富有单身汉不觉无聊吗
...but doesn't the gold-plated-bachelor bit get a little stale?
我猜和寂寞秘书一样
A lot like the lonely-secretary syndrome, l guess.
执行助理
Executive Assistant.
抱歉
Sorry.
秘书
Secretary.
有女朋友吗？
Any girlfriend?
当然
Sure
你是指...认真的？
You mean, as in serious?
没有，有过一个，不成功 出了什么差错？
Had one, didn't work. What went wrong? Hang on!
慢着，我想我知道
l think l know!
你对她隐瞒秘密？ 不，我将一切告诉她
You kept things from her. l told her everything.
而那个事实吓到了她？
The truth frightened her?
有两个事实
There are two truths...
你知道吗？
...you know?
而她无法调和二者 因为我也无法调和二者
She had trouble reconciling them because l had trouble... ...reconciling them.
是
Yes
若维琪以为... 维琪？
Vicki thought-- Vicki?
溜冰好手或空姐？
lce skater or stewardess?
不，她是个摄影记者
No, she was a photojournalist.
对你双重性的困扰 维琪的看法对吗？
Was Vicki right about your... ...difficulty with duality?
我若说是，那...
You see... ...if l say yes, then...
你会以为我是杀人狂...
...you'll think of me as a... ...Norman Bates, a Ted Bundy type and...
也许不肯让我吻你
You might not let me kiss you.
会令人失望的 一向是所谓的正常人
lt's the so-called normal guys who always let you down.
狂人从未吓到我 至少他们执着
Sicko's never scare me. At least they're committed.
是
Yeah
不，我不能那么做 我也是
l can't do that. Neither can l.
这是特别报导 冰雪公主被绑架了
The lce Princess has been kidnapped. This is a special bulletin.
戈登署长，你能证实 蝙蝠侠涉嫌绑架的传闻吗
Can you confirm Batman's suspected involvement in the abduction?
这个证据纯粹是间接的
The evidence is purely circumstantial.
它沾了血迹
This was found, stained with blood,
是在失踪女孩的 更衣室找到的
in the missing girl's dressing room.
我得走了... 不，是我，这是你的家
-l must go. -No, it's your house.
慢着，坐一下，好吗？ 轻松点，我马上回来
Hold on. Just sit for a second. Relax and l'll be right back.
阿福，我得到广场去 我看到了
l've got to go to the plaza.
是，我知道 他简直是在求我出现
-He is begging me to show. -l hoped you'd snub him.
因此我希望你别理他 不行，那是绑架案
l can't. lt's kidnapping.
听着，我要你这么做
Here's what you'll do.
糟糕
Shit!
告诉瑟琳娜 就是里面的凯尔小姐
Tell Selina, Ms. Kyle,
告诉她...我得进城去
l had to go out of town
告诉她... 我突然有笔大生意要处理
.Tell her l had a big business deal or-- You know what?
不，这样吧，告诉她... 让她知道...
Let her know,way--
不是用愚蠢的 “做我女友”的方法
not in some kind of dumb, ''be-my-girlfriend''
我会转达讯息的 太好了
l'll relay the message.
凯尔小姐？ 阿福
Ms. Kyle,
韦恩先生叫我告诉你... 韦恩先生？布鲁斯，对
Mr. Wayne told me to tell you that-- Bruce, yes.
可否代我告诉他 我历经许多...改变...
Would you tell him... ...l've been going through... a lot of changes and....
不，只要告诉他 我的突然离去并非拒绝
Just that... ...this is not a rejection...
事实上，他使我觉得有
...my abruptly leaving. ln fact, he makes me feel the way...
我希望真的是的感受
...l hope l really am.
不！
No
你能编个借口或什么吗 我正好想到一个
Could you just make up a sonnet or... a dirty limerick? One has just sprung to mind.
谢谢 这边，夫人
This way, ma'am.
抱歉
Sorry
女士先生们
Ladies and Gentlemen.
女士先生们 请注意一下好吗？
Please, may l have your attention?
我知道对许多人而言 近来高谭似乎祸患频仍
l know that to many of you... ...Gotham seems a bit beleaguered these days.
但我要你们知道
But l want you to know your elected officials...
你们选的官员与警方 已经控制住情势
...and your police department... ...have the situation well in hand.
会痛的 谢谢你
Gotta hurry. Thank you.
这是陷阱 好让人觉得是我做的
lt was set up.
别担心，我会告诉警方
l'll tell the police
我是被一个有鱼腥味的 丑鸟人绑架的
l was kidnapped by an ugly birdman with fish breath.
有人提到鱼吗？
Did somebody say fish?
我整天都未进食呢！
l haven't been fed all day.
吃地板吧
Eat floor.
高织
High fiber.
帅哥
Hey, stud...
我以为我们互相吸引
-...l thought we had something together.
没错
-We do.
得走了
Got to go.
女孩子的悄悄话
Girl talk.
她放我走了
She let me go.
我想是因为我以女孩立场 跟她讲理
l reasoned with her, girl-to-girl.
小心，别动
Be careful. Don't move.
草地飞镖
Lawn dart!
有翅膀的老鼠 做拿手的事吧
Rats with wings, do your thing.
蝙蝠侠推落冰雪公主
Batman pushed the Princess!
停火！
Hold your fire!
你对我这种女孩 很有吸引力
You're catnip to a girl like me.
英俊，迷人 值得付出一切代价
Handsome, dazed... ...and to die for.
你若吃w寄生会致命
Mistletoe can be deadly if you eat it.
但你若认真，吻更致命
But a kiss... ...can be even deadlier if you mean it.
你是这周第二个杀我的人
You're the second man who killed me this week.
但我还剩七条命
But l've got seven lives left.
我试过救你
l tried to save you--
似乎你企图救的每个女人 结果都死了
Seems like every woman you try to save ends up dead.
或大为责怪你
Or deeply resentful.
也许你该退休了
Maybe you should retire.
可恶！
Damn.
真出色
Outstanding.
你是包装成性感 圣诞礼物的美女与野兽
You're Beauty and the Beast... ...in one luscious Christmas gift pack.
你说你只要吓吓冰雪公主
You said you'd scare the lce Princess.
我觉得她看来蛮怕的
She looked pretty scared to me.
来点香槟？
Touch of the bubbly?
我们还在等我们 让我们结合圆房吧
So what are we waiting for? Let's consummate our fiendish union.
你在说些什么？
What?
别这样，你无法想像吗
Oh, come on. Can't you picture?
市长的华宅一片黑暗
lt's the Mayor's mansion.
我精疲力尽 于是你进卧室
l'm bushed, so here you come into the bedroom...
扭着你的小尾巴
...twitching your little tail...
一手拿我的拖鞋 一手拿杯纯马丁尼  拜托
...my slippers in one hand, a dry martini in the other. Please.
我无论如何不会碰你 你这差劲的妞儿
l wouldn't touch you to scratch you.
我该阉掉你 你发出了所有的讯号
You lousy minx! l'll have you spayed! You sent out all the signals!
我想我不再喜欢你了
l don't think l like you anymore!
再见，我未参加的人 上天堂吧
Good-bye, my unintended. Go to heaven.
谢谢
Thank you
他在这
There he is!
别调整荧幕
Don't adjust your sets.
欢迎光临 奥兹瓦卡伯波特驾驶学校
Welcome... ...to the Oswald Cobblepot School of Driving.
各位先生，开始尖叫吧
Gentlemen, start your screaming.
也许此时提起，时机不对 但我的驾照过期了
This may be a bad time to mention it, but my license is expired!
轻松点
Relax.
我会对付高谭市那些 爱抱怨的讨厌白痴木偶的
l'll take care of the squealing, wretched, pinhead puppets of Gotham!
我玩弄这个臭城市 于掌股之间
You must admit l play this stinking city like a harp from hell!
十二点方向 有个无助的老太太
Helpless old lady at 12 o'clock high!
真奇怪
That's funny.
好啦，现在我有点担心了
Now l'm a little worried.
他就算活着，也不用担心 别紧张
So he survived. Why worry? He didn't even lose a limb!
他连四肢都没少一点 眼球，失禁都没有
An eyeball! Bladder control!
重点是听听他们 他们对旧象征已失去信心
Listen to them. They've lost faith in old symbols.
他们已认同你 是未来的代表了
They'll bond with you, the icon of the future.
若是成功，便别改变
lf it works, don't fix it.
我们今晚在我的 面具舞会上庆祝
We'll celebrate tonight at my annual ball...
许瑞克和卡伯波特 耀眼的联盟
...Shreck and Cobblepot... ...the visionary alliance.
走吧
Go
在维护我们这个 美丽城市的时刻
When it came time... ...to ensure the safety of our fair city...
市长有计划吗？
...did the Mayor have a plan?
没有
No!
他依赖一个人
He relied on a man.
一个蝙蝠侠
A Batman.
一个行动炸弹 最后终于爆炸的化妆疯子
A ticking time-bomb of a costumed freak...
我们主要关切的 是这个可怕的怪物
Our prime concern is this ghastly grotesque.
但也别忘了修蝙蝠车
But let's not forget about repairing the Batmobile.
得考虑安全问题
There's security to consider.
我们不能任意将它 送到一个修车厂，对吧
We can't just take it to any old body shop.
安全问题？
Security?
谁让维琪维尔进蝙蝠洞
Who let Vicki Vale into the Batcave?
我正在工作 一转身，她便在那里
l'm working and l turn around. There she is.
“嗨，维琪，进来”
''Hi, Vick. Come on in.''
准备好了吗 我想我走楼梯
-Ready? -l'll take the stairs.
你们问我 我是否为个人荣耀上场
You ask...am l up here for personal glory?
不是
No.
我受苦多年
快乐的藏身于 你们的大道下方
我渴望重新捕捉的荣耀 是高谭的荣耀
The glory that l yearn to recapture... ...is the glory of Gotham!
（频道锁定）
我要如何达成
How can this be accomplished?
我知道你们都很关心
l know... ...you're all concerned.
轻松点
Relax.
我玩弄这个臭城市 于掌股之间
l'll take care of the squealing, wretched, pinhead puppets of Gotham.
我没有那么说
l didn't say that.
你得承认
You must admit l played this stinking city...
我玩弄这个臭城市 于掌股之间
...like a harp from hell!
你得承认
You must admit...
我玩弄这个臭城市 于掌股之间
...l played this stinking city like a harp from hell!
等一下！
为何老是有人带着 蛋和番茄去听演讲
Why does someone always bring eggs and tomatoes to a speech?
他在那里
There is he
我的宝贝们
My babies.
你们想我吗？
Did you miss me?
很棒的演讲，奥兹瓦
Great speech, Oswald.
我不叫奥兹瓦
My name is not Oswald!
是企鹅
lt's Penguin!
我不是人类
l am not a human being!
我是动物，是冷血的
l am an animal. Cold-blooded!
冷气转强
Crank the A.C.!
我的名单呢？ 将名字送上来
Where are my lists?! Bring me the names!
时候到了 这是高谭市长子的名字
lt's time. These are the names of the first-born sons of Gotham City.
就和我一样
Just like l was.
而和我一样
And like me,
可怕的命运在等着他们
a terrible fate waits for them.
当他们的父母狂欢时 他们将在摇篮软床上做梦
Tonight, while their parents party... ...they'll be dreaming away...
我们将劫走他们 将他们带到下水道
...in their safe cribs... ...their soft beds... ...and we'll snatch them... ...carry them into the sewer...
将他们丢入深黑水墓中
...and toss them into a deep, dark, watery grave.
企鹅
Penguin?
杀死熟睡儿童 岂不是有一点...
Killing sleeping children... ...isn't that a little...
不，是很多
No, it's a lot.
韦恩先生，提醒你
A reminder. Tonight is
今晚那个怪许瑞克先生 要举行讨厌的派对
that loathsome party hosted by the odious Mr. Shreck.
我们能严正回绝吗？ 没兴趣
May we R.S.V.P. in the resoundingly negative? Not interested.
不过...
Although...
瑟琳娜凯尔可能会在场
...Selina Kyle might be there.
真出色的服装
lngenious costume.
我来猜猜看，基金会好人
Let me guess. Trust-fund goodie-goodie.
感觉很好吧？
Feeling good?
你差点使一个怪物 当上高谭市长
You almost made a monster of the Mayor of Gotham City.
我是本市之光
l am the light of this City...
我是它的恶毒扭曲灵魂
...and l am its mean, twisted soul.
谁当市长有关系吗？ 对我而言是的
Does it matter who's Mayor? To me.
无聊
Yawn.
听着，昨天很抱歉
l'm sorry about yesterday, but l had...
我得去处理一笔大生意 没关系
...a pretty big deal come through. Fall through, actually.
我得回家去喂我的猫
lt's okay. l had to go home and feed my cat.
那不伤感情罗？
No hard feelings, then?
事实上
Actually...
应该是半伤
...semihard, l'd say.
寝具部有个 大而舒适的双人床
There's a big, comfy California King over in Bedding.
你说我们...
Why don't we....
脱掉舞会服装吗？
Take off our costumes?
我想我已厌倦戴面具了
l'm tired of wearing masks.
我也是
Me too.
让我问你一件事
Tell me something.
你今晚为何来？
Why'd you come tonight?
你先说 来看你
-You first. -To see you.
说得真好
Lovely.
但愿我能说同样的话 但我是为了麦斯来的
l wish l could say the same, but l came for Max.
什么意思？你和...
Do you mean you...
不可能是你和麦斯
...and Max...
我和麦斯！
Me and Max?
不！
No
这个和麦斯
No. This and Max.
不！
No
别告诉我杀死麦斯 无法解决一切，会的
Don't tell me killing Max won't solve anything, because it will.
你不厌倦这虚伪强盗大亨 老是获胜吗？
Aren't you tired of this sanctimonious robber-baron...
他应该被埋在六尺下才对
...coming out on top? He should be six feet under.
我确信你和你老板之间 有许多问题
You may have problems with your boss,
但是，你以为你是什么人
but who do you think you are?
我已经不知道了 布鲁斯
l don't know anymore, Bruce.
w寄生下的吻
A kiss under the mistletoe.
你知道，吃w寄生会致命
Mistletoe can be deadly if you eat it.
但你若认真
But a kiss can be even deadlier...
吻更致命
...if you mean it.
我的天
Oh, my God.
这是否意味 我们得开始再打斗
Do we have to start fighting?
我们到外面去
Let's go outside.
父亲！  我的儿子 你没事吧？  是，我很好
-Are you okay? -l'm all right.
你们没邀我 因此我不请自来
You didn't invite me... ...so l crashed!
你要做什么？
What do you want?
现在，我的部队正在全城 搜寻你们的孩子
Right now, my troops are fanning out across town for your children!
对，你们的长子
Yes! For your first-born sons!
你们使他无助在家的那个
The ones you left defenseless at home... ...so you could dress up like jerks...
好让你们能打扮得像傻瓜 喝酒，尽情跳舞
...get juiced and dance... ...badly!
我亲自来抓高谭最心爱的 儿子，奇普许瑞克先生
l've personally come... ...for Gotham's favorite son... ...Mr. Chip Shreck.
跟我走，你这个大白痴 以便死于下面的下水道中
Come with me, you great white dope! To die, way down in the sewer!
就抓我吧 别抓奇普
Not Chip. lf you have any human feeling, take me instead.
你若有丝毫人性 我没有，因此，不行
l don't. So, no!
我才是你要的
l'm the one you want.
问你自己，操纵背叛你的 不是麦斯许瑞克吗？
lsn't it Max Shreck who manipulated and betrayed you? lsn't it Max, not Chip...
你要看到他淹死的 不是麦斯吗？
...you want to immerse to his eyeballs in raw sewage?
好吧，你说的有理
Okay, you got a point.
我就暂时让小王子活着
l'll let the little prince live, for now.
进鸭子里去
ln the duck!
实在太好了
This is going to be good...
在高谭最有希望的作物 成熟前，将它们砍断
...to cut down a whole crop of Gotham's most promising... ...before their prime.
你问我如何引诱他们？
You asked me...how do l lure them in?
一点“吹笛企鹅”把戏
A little ''Pied Penguin'' action.
你可以看着他们沉入一池 你的工业副产品中
And you get to watch them sink... ...into a deep puddle... ...of your industrial by-products.
然后
Then...
你再加入他们
...you join them.
快点将那些孩子装好 好吗？
Hurry up and get those kids loaded.
这边走，孩子们 来吧，跟我走
Right this way, kiddies. Come with me.
所有的儿童呢？
So where are all the children?
“爱亲的企鹅 儿童们懊悔不克参加”
''Dear Penguin; ''The children regret they're unable to attend.
“蝙蝠侠”
''Batman!''
我亲爱的企鹅们
My dear penguins...
我们站在一个大关键上
...we stand on a great threshold!
害怕是正常的
lt's okay to be scared!
你们有许多人将回不来
Many of you won't be coming back.
多谢蝙蝠侠
Thanks to Batman...
惩罚所有 神的子女的时刻到了
...the time has come... ...to punish all God's children!
长子，次子，三子，四子
First-, second-, third- and fourth-born!
为何要有偏见？ 男性和女生
Why be biased? Male and female!
性别平等
Hell, the sexes are equal...
和他们的性感带炸入空中
...with their erogenous zones... ...blown sky-high!
向前走
Forward... ...march!
解放高谭行动开始
The liberation of Gotham... ...has begun!
企鹅们在地面上活动了
The penguins are moving above ground.
企鹅军接近发射目的地 高谭广场
Penguin army... ...approaching launch destination at Gotham Plaza.
距燃点一分钟
One minute until ignition.
他们不尊重我 我就让他们送命
They wouldn't put me on a pedestal... ...so l'm laying them on a slab!
企鹅似乎在高谭广场集结
Penguins converging on Gotham Plaza.
距燃点三十秒
30 seconds until ignition.
发射后估计死亡人数 十万人
Estimated casualties after launch; 100,000 people.
企鹅们已抵达高谭广场
The penguins have reached Gotham Square.
距发射十五秒
15 seconds to ignition.
准备好了，先生
Ready, sir.
我已定好座标
Got the coordinates.
10 9 8 7！
10，9，8，7
好了，让他们转向 是，先生
Let's turn them around.
（频率锁定）
情况不对
Something is wrong.
讯号被干扰了
The signal is jammed.
他们似乎转向了
They seem to be turning around.
过来 还有某种东西 往这边来了
There is also something coming this way.
非常大，非常快
Very large. Very fast.
谁在那里
Who's there?!
好，我要定出讯号来源了
Homing in on the signal's origin.
你嫉妒我是个真正怪物 而你得戴面具
You're jealous because l'm a genuine freak... ...and you have to wear a mask!
也许你说得对
You might be right.
但唯一重要的是 谁拿着雨伞
But what it all comes down to is; who's holding the umbrella?
我的宝贝
My babies! !
我不知道你有何所求
l don't know what you want,
但我知道只要一点功夫 就能为你弄到手
but l can get it with a minimum of fuss.
钱...珠宝
Money. Jewels.
很大的一串珠宝
A very big ball of string.
你的血，麦斯 我的血？
Your blood, Max.
我在办公室捐过了
l gave at the office.
只有半品脱 我要的是半加仑
A half-pint. l'm talking gallons.
我们来谈条件
Let's make a deal!
除了我的血 我能为你做什么？
Other than my blood, what can l do?
抱歉，麦斯，以死还死
Sorry, Max. A die for a die.
你不只在救一条命 也是在救...  闭嘴！
You're not just saving a life-- Shut up. You're going to jail.
你要去坐牢了
别天真了
Don't be naive.
法律对他或我们这种人 都莫可奈何
The law doesn't apply to people like him...or us.
二者皆非
Wrong on both counts.
你为何要如此做？
Why do this?
我们将他交给警方
Let's just take him to the police.
然后我们可以一起回家
Then we can go home... ...together.
瑟琳娜...
Selina...
你不懂吗？
...don't you see?
我们是一样的
We're the same.
由中间分裂为二
Split... ...down the center.
瑟琳娜，拜托
Please.
布鲁斯
Bruce...
我愿意和你 住在你的城堡中
l would love to live with you in your castle...
直到永远 一如童话故事
...forever, just like in a fairy tale.
但我就是无法忍受自己
l just couldn't live with myself.
因此，别假装这是个 快乐结局  瑟琳娜
Don't pretend this is a happy ending.
瑟琳娜凯尔
Selina Kyle.
你被开除了
You're fired.
还有布鲁斯韦恩
And Bruce Wayne...
你为何做蝙蝠侠的打扮
...why are you dressed up like Batman?
因为他是蝙蝠侠 你这低能儿
Because he is Batman, you moron!
以前是
Was.
不要
Don't.
你杀我，企鹅杀我 蝙蝠侠杀我
You killed me, the Penguin killed me, Batman killed me.
去掉三条命 你有足够子弹解决我吗
Three lives down. Got enough to finish me off?!
只有一个办法能知道
One way to find out.
4 5
Four. Five.
仍然活着
Still alive!
Six.
7，好女孩都上天堂
Seven. All good girls go to heaven.
还剩两条命
Two lives left.
我想该留下一条 过明年圣诞节
l'll save one for next Christmas.
但在这同时...
But in the meantime...
吻一下，如何？ 圣诞老人
...how about a kiss, Santie Claus?
Shit!
可恶，选到一把可爱的
l picked a cute one.
热气使我不舒服
The heat's getting to me.
我马上就谋杀你
l'll murder you momentarily.
但首先，我需要喝冰水
But first... ...l need a cool drink... ...of ice water.
阿福，停车
Stop the car.
无论如何 圣诞快乐，韦恩先生
Come what may... ...Merry Christmas, Mr. Wayne.
圣诞快乐，阿福
Merry Christmas, Alfred.
“平安归于人”
Goodwill toward men.
和女人
And women.
剧终